Daniel Morales

+1 858 429 9920 · danieldev0612@gmail.com · github.com/smartdev0612

Biography

Senior Front End Engineer & Seasoned Engineering Leader & Consultant with 10+ years of experience designing and building responsive web design and mobile apps in the software industry. Proficient with CSS and JS Frameworks and extensive UX and user psychology knowledge. Notable achievements include boosting the conversion rate of an existing website by 80% with improved code and design.

Experience

Senior Front End Engineer, Health Blockchain Security Services Illinois, US

Jan 2021 – present

HCISS is a Blockchain cybersecurity startup. This company created and maintains the BSECA platform to analyze blockchain network transactions.

- Contributed to the BSECA platform development using Next.js, TypeScript, Node.js, TailwindCSS, MongoDB, Docker, Kubernetes, Microservices and AWS
- Improved UI/UX design through brainstorming with designers
- Built Web3.0 applications such as ICO, DeFi platforms and NFT marketplaces using Solidity, Truffle Suite, Web3.js, React.js, Redux toolkit, Mocha and Chai
- Daily maintenance of code, debugging issues, and solving clients' problems
- Prevented potential bugs by using unit testing for React components and backend APIs
- Presented findings clearly and concisely to key decision-makers
- Collaborated with different team leads to define the best practices and engineering standards within teams
- Agile Project management through Monday.com

Senior Front End Engineer, FixMyCar

Feb 2017 - Dec 2020

Michigan, US

FixMyCar is a tech-enabled car maintenance subscription service

- Developed mobile responsive e-commerce pages based on the Figma design
- Organized codes by using custom hooks and React components
- Showed dynamic data using GraphQL
- Improved SEO and page loading speed by using browser cache, SSR and image optimization
- Built RESTful APIs using Node.js and Express.js, integrated 3rd party APIs
- Created CI/CD workflow by using Github actions
- Strong experience with DevOps on GCP platform
- Worked with an agile team of 12 members and provided end-to-end solutions for clients
- Actively communicated with stakeholders, business/product people and designers to keep the ball rolling and engaged problem solving when needed to unblock engineers

Front End Developer, LEDEFLY

Sep 2016 – Jan 2017

Montevideo, UY

- Implemented Figma design using React Material-UI library, created fully customized components
- Accelerated page loading speed by using SSR and SSG
- Managed global states of React components by using Context API, Redux, and Saga

• Built SEO-friendly web pages by adding metadata and proper keywords

Front End Developer, Techno Software

Kuala Lumpur, MY

Aug 2015 - Aug 2016

- Maintained the internal and management website of the company
- Created fitness web application using React.js, Bootstrap, and Firebase
- Developed a well-organized frontend by creating customized components
- Built mobile responsive and pixel perfect front-end using Bootstrap and Material UI
- Direct communication with CTO to improve the workflow

Technical Intern, HCLTech

Apr 2011 – Jul 2015

Kuala Lumpur, MY

- Studied fundamental knowledge of web development
- Faced with practical situations and learned how to work within a team

Education and skills

University of Malaya	2011
Bachelors of Science in Computer Science	
Microservices with Node JS and React Certificate	2023
Software Architecture & Design of Modern Large Scale Systems Certificate	2022
Complete Next.js Developer in 2022: Zero to Mastery Certificate	2022

Languages

Malay – native English – proficient

Tech Skills:

Full Stack web application development, mockup and wireframe design, RESTful API building, GraphQL, JavaScript, React.js, Next.js, React Redux, Node.js, Tailwind CSS, TypeScript, jQuery, Jest, Mocha, MongoDB, MySQL, PostgreSQL, Docker, Git, AWS, GCP, Heroku